Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Buno, Paul, May 4, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Grand Canyon, AZ. Interview by Al Whiting regarding songs by Paul Buno... Havasupai Indian Music -- Opening verse, Peach dance song -- Death song (Mohave mourning song) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.71 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker, March 26, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Bonaparte's retreat, and another untitled violin tune performed by Paul Bailey... Interview by Al Whiting concerns Bailey's life and music...; Pre-1980-1/D.73
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker, March 11, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Billy Vanero -- Bloomer Johnson --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.74
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baily, Paul, April 9, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by Paul Bailey: Lord Ullin's daughter -- Disscussion of "Lord Ullin's daughter" with Al Whiting -- Poor Caroline (tune only) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.76
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker, March 25, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by Paul Bailey and Gladys Barker...Lowland's low -- Green grow the lilacs --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.77
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baily, Paul, March 25, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Performed by Paul Bailey: Utah Carl --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.78
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Wadleigh, Atherton B., May, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Performed by Atherton B. Wadleigh...Fragments of: Old Thompson had an old gray mule -- I went to call on Miss McGee -- Dime porque me enganste -- Bury me not on the lone prarie --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.79
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Recording by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Sunrise song -- Want some Piki -- Approaching song -- Hopi versions of Comanche songs -- Mixed dancers' song -- ]; SWF PRE1980.1/D.81
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Recording by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Hopi buffalo dance song -- Hopi butterfly dance song -- Hopi version of a Navajo buffalo dance song -- Mixed dance Katchinas song -- Hopi version of a Navajo dance song -- ]; SWF PRE1980.1/D.82
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Recorded by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Hopi long hair dance song -- Closing song -- ]; Local Call Number: SWF PRE1980.1/D.83
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tumacacori, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performed by Mr. Morris: A Church without a bishop, a state without a king -- Poor Tom, a sea song -- The Old hen flew over in the garden...Performed by Mrs. Morris: If I were queen of France --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.84
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performers are Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris...Sir Robert Kilaloo (Mrs. Morris) -- Some folks love to say (Mrs. Morris) --A Family that once resided in the very same thoroughfare that I did (Mr. Morris) -- A Little peach in an orchard grew -- Listen to my tale of woe (Mr. Morris) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.85
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performed by Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris: I'm Romeo -- Oh where have you been Billy Boy...Performed by Mr. Morris: Let's go home -- No more walking in the moonlight -- tale of woe (Mr. Morris) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.86
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Juan Urias, December 31, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performances by unknown girls, Alvesa Hummel, and Juan Urias of three songs...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.87
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan and Alvesa Hummel, December 31, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performed by Juan Urias: Song, Part II -- Laughing song, Part II -- Crying song, Part I...Performed by Alvesa Hummel: La Indita --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.88
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J., Alvesa Hummel and Juan Urias, December 31, 1953; December 31, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Freighting from Wilcox to Globe (A.J. Busby) -- I'm poor, I'm old and only in the way (A.J. Busby) -- Las Mananitas (Alvesa Hummel) -- Laughing song, Part I (Juan Urias) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.89
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J., December 31, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performed by A.J. Busby: Freighting from Wilcox to Globe -- The Sheriff's sale -- Dixie -- Nice young Mormons --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.90
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Eleece, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Mrs. Wm. Gaston -- [Negro blues] and work songs --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.91
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May 12, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Robin bird song (Phoenix) -- There's a spot that I know (Coolidge) -- No home for the poor (Tempe) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.92
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May 12, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laborabory. Way down in old St. Francis Bottom (Tucson) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.93
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pueblo Grande Museum; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with introduction and concluding remarks by Odd S. Halseth...Cochiti songs include: Chaquenna -- Travel song -- Cradle song - - Daybreak song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.94
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with introduction and concluding remarks by Odd S. Halseth...Green corn dance (Cochiti) -- War chants (the last war chant with English insert "Lord bring them home", Cochiti) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.95
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded by Odd S. Halseth...Navajo yebichi: Eagle-in-the-air Narrow eagle -- Seneca false face song -- Navajo yebichi songs: Eagle-in-the-air (complete) -- Narrow eagle (incomplete) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.96
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with comments by Odd S. Halseth...Caddo stomp dance -- Zuni corn dance -- Jemez hunting or arrow dance -- Kiowa round dance -- Kiowa war dance -- Taos round dance --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.98 90
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with comments by Odd S. Halseth...Pima kingfisher song -- Pima Ka-a-ghem -- Cocopa ilcha "Bird song" -- Cocopa karuk -- Apache gahan (White Mountain) -- Apache gahan (Mescalero) -- Comanche peyote song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.99
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J., 1954; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Carroll Rinehart...Keeley cure -- Freighting from Wilcox to Globe -- I'm just forty-five and my dear little wife -- Hose cart song -- A Passing policeman found a little child -- Near a cottage in the twilight -- Stood a soldier and a maid -- My grandfather's farm --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.100
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J., 1954; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Carroll Rinehart...Sheriff's sale -- Engagement ring -- On the baggage coach ahead -- Miss Fogarty's Christmas cake -- Nice young Mormons -- Old and only in the way -- Are you staying, staying, in the tender shepherd's fold?; SWF PRE1980.1/D.101
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Mormon pioneer pageant, July 24, 1954; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; St. David, AZ. Recorded by Desmond Powell and Carl Ketoham at the Mormon Pioneer Pageant...Introductory narrative (Mrs. Tilloston) -- Pioneer song -- interview -- Grandmother's diary -- Account of Brigham Young -- Account of departure from Nauvoo -- Burial of a child on the plains...Continued on Pre-1980-1/D.103...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.102
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Mormon pioneer pageant, July 24, 1954; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; St. David, AZ. Recording is a continuation of Pre-1980-1/D.102...Recorded by Desmond Powell and Carl Ketoham at the Mormon Pioneer Pageant...Narrative: Festivities en route -- Dance: Tiptoe through the tulips -- Narrative: Indians tableau -- Narrative: German Mormons -- Speech on LDS in modern Germany -- Narrative: Hardships en route -- Speech by Bringham Young, tableau -- Narrative: Persecutions, army -- Tableau: Bringham Young with army officers -- Narrative: Drafting of husband -- Handcarts -- Handcart song -- Come, come, ye saints --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.103
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Colladay, Diana, Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez, May 13, 1954; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by V[icente] Acosta...Cancion de cuna (Diana Colladay) -- Proverbs (Diana Colladay) -- Cancion de primavera (Diana Colladay, accompanied by Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez) -- Corrido de los dos hermanos (Frank Rodriguez and Ralph Corrales) -- Corrido de Santa Amalia (Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez) -- Corrido de Jose Lisorio (Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez)... Colladay, Corrales, and Rodriguez were students at Tucson Senior High School...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.104
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Colladay, Diana, V[icente] Acosta, Herb Burrows, and Guadalupe Armenta, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by V[icente] Acosta...Tres hojitas (Diana Colladay) -- La Realera, camp follower (V[icente] Acosta) -- Preguntale a las estrellas (V[icente] Acosta and Herb Burrows) -- Corridos recited by Guadalupe Armenta: El Cautivo, a famous race horse -- El Desertor -- Luisita -- El Real de Guadalupe -- Abraham Lincoln...Incomplete interview between Vicente S. Acosta and Armenta on the "gaucho slang" (continued on Pre-1980-1/D.106-107)...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.105
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Armenta, Sr. Guadalupe, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Sound disc contains continuation of interview with Mr. Guadalupe Armenta by Vicente S. Acosta on gaucho slang...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.106
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Brannen, Charlie, Ed Gardner and Guadalupe Armenta, Summer, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson and Patagonia, AZ. Sound disc contains three distinct recordings: My name is Charlie Brannen, sung by Travis Edmonson and recorded by Carl Ketcham, Tucson, Arizona, 1953...In old Nogales, sung by Ed Gardner and recorded by Doris Seibold in Patagonia, Arizona...Continuation of an interview by Vicente S. Acosta with Mr. Guadalupe Armenta on gaucho slang, recorded in Tucson, Arizona...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.107
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Stevens, Jess, April, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Sound disc contains part one of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache) by Larry Kellner, and includes an Apache dance-chant...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.108
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Stevens, Jess, April, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Sound disc contains part of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache), recorded Larry Kellner, and includes an Apache dance-chant...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.109
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interviews, Fellows, Mr. Clinton D., Winter, 1955; April, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Sound disc contains the end of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache), recorded by Larry Kellner...Mr. Fellows performs the sing-song method of learning [the] alphabet and [multiplication] tables in his youth in Vandalia, Michigan...Also contains some nonsense syllable rhymes...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.110
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, England, Judy, November 19, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Carmen, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting...There was a Phillipine hombre -- Song in many languages - Que sorry es la vida -- "Italian" song -- Alas, mi vida - yo soy tu querer -- The Old grey mare -- Nocodemus [Nicodemus] the slave -- The Prodigal son -- Nurse's song -- Serán las dos -- There once was an hombre -- Game song from Sonora and a discussion of going to school there --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.111
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Clark Myron, May 1, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Carmen, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting...Devils' Roping (Myron Clark) -- Ninety eight bottles of beer on the wall (sung in chorus by Boy Scout Troops [66 & 96]) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.112
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee Katie, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. "Sung by Katie Lee and her guitar"...Trail herding song (music by Katie Lee) -- Spanish is the loving tongue -- Johnny Ringo (music by Katie Lee, and chorus added by her) -- Wee little Paiute (written in last five years by Cassie Monson and A.R. Syman of Monticello, Utah) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.113
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee Katie, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. "Sung by Katie Lee and her guitar"...Blue Mountain (written by Cassie Monson -- Lolita (music by Katie Lee) -- The Frisco Peaks (Tyin' knots in the devil's tail) -- Lasca (music by Katie Lee) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.114
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, La Farge, Pete, February, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. The Pony called Nell -- Walkin' John -- 'Twas in the spring time of the year -- The Key to the highway blues -- Yavapai Pete --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.115
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, La Farge, Pete, February, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Blues: Now Betty told Dupris, "Get me a dime" -- The Ballad of Roger Young -- The Old Chisholm Trail --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.116
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Can I sleep in your brain tonight, Mister? -- Butcher's bay -- East bound train -- Kitty Wells -- Lover of lone Green Valley --; Pre-1980-1/D.117
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...I got no use for the women -- Letter from home sweet home -- My mother the queen of my heart -- Jack and Joe -- Little Mohee -- When the work's all done this fall -- Maple on the hill -- Put your little foot -- Tennessee waltz -- Golden slippers --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.118
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. My Juanita -- Little Joe -- The Wrangler -- Little Joe -- The Wrangler's sister Nell -- Floyd Collins -- Beer barrel polka --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.119
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Hobo Bill -- Wreck of ol' Number Nine -- Punchin' the dough -- Charlie Rutledge -- My pretty quadroon -- Moonlight and skies --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.120
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Miller, Bob, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Bob Miller at the Elkhorn Ranch near Sasabee, Arizona: Hoe-down -- Hobo Bill -- Windy Bill -- Days of '49 -- The God damn wheel -- The Bad Brahma bull --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.121
  Original Collector: Ben E. Timian
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Shreeves, Charles, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Sung by Charles Shreeves: Bad Brahma bull -- The Zebra dun -- The Strawberry roan -- A Cowboy's dance song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.122
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee, Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. and Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian in Flagstaff...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Careless love -- Wayfaring stranger -- Long time ago -- Sometimes I feel like a motherless child -- Barbara [Allen?] Ellen -- Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith: Your mother still prays for you, Jack -- Cowboy Jack -- I'll be hanged if they're going to hang me -- Fort Dix boogie --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.123
  Original Collector: Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Mistletoe bough -- Takes a worried man to sing a worried song -- Goodby little darling -- I'll be all smiles tonight -- Green grow the lilacs -- Dreary, black hills -- Marching to Pretoria -- Delia -- Way back in the hills -- Roundup lullaby --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.124
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Down in the valley -- My pretty quadroon -- Two brothers -- Streets of Laredo -- Zebra dunn -- To the fox -- If I were a blackbird --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.125
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Elias, Araella F., Sra. Refrigio Aguirre Elias, Juan Elias Marcos, and Alfred Elias, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Aravelea F. Elias... Continuation of interview of a party at her house about old-time Mexican remedies, tales, festival customs, foods, etc... Interview in Spanish and English... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.126
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Elias, Aravella F., May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Aravella F. Elias... Continuation of Aravella F. Elias interview about old-time Mexican remedies, tales, festival customs, and foods in Tucson... Interview in Spanish with some English... Interview in four parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.127
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Diamos de Grazia, Alexandra, April 15, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Alexandra Diamos de Grazia about Mexican tales and legends... In English... Songs include: El Tejano -- El Merino… Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.128
  Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Diamos de Grazia, Alexandra, April 15, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of Alexandra Diamos de Grazia interview about Mexican folktales and legends in Tucson... Interview in English... Songs include: El Tejano -- El Merino -- San Xavier… Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.129
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Richards, A.L., Mrs. A.L. Richards, and Marciana Rejon, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of Mr. and Mrs. A.L. Richards interview about tales and legends from Sonora (Mexico) and Tucson... Marciana Rejon talks about tales and legends from Colima, Guaymas and Tucson... Interview complete in three parts... In Spanish... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.130
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Rejon, Marciana and Norma Santa Ana, may, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Miss Marciana Rejon talks about tales and legends from Colina, Guaymas and Tucson, in Spanish... Interview complete in three parts... Miss Norma Santa Ana tells a story from Springer, New Mexico, in English...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.131
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Rios, Margot and Julia Ortega, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Interview complete in tow parts... Margot Rios tells stories from Nogales and Sonora, in English... El en cuentro del Sr. Pimienta con El Diablo -- La Muchacha emtorujada -- Las Tres manos... Julia Ortega tells the Sonoran story, El Diablo de la montaña... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.132
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interviews, Espinosa de Garcia, Mrs. Matilde, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Mrs. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia about Yaqui and Sonoran tales and legends... In Spanish... Interview complete in seven parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.133
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Espinosa de Garcia, Mrs. Matilde, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Mrs. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia about Yaqui and Sonoran tales and legends... In Spanish... Interview complete in seven parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.134
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Narratives, Rosenthal, Mrs. Eva and Sr. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia, May, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... The Black dog as devil -- El Tesoro de Indio (Mrs. Eva Rosenthal, Sonora) -- El Tesora de General (Mrs. Eva Rosenthal, Sonora) -- Girl from Douglas and poltergeist -- Crucifix in Magdalena -- Conclusion of interview with Sr. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.136
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Valenzuela, Guadalupe Jose, Dave and Tony Yubeta, Donald Price, and Tila Escalada, May 14, 1960; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Nogalse, [AZ]. Recorded by KNOG, Nogales, for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Are you teasing me? (Tony and Dave Yubeta) -- A Pretty woman is a deadly weapon (Tony Yubeta) -- Old Nogales (Donald Price, age 17, learned form an old recording by Edw. Gardner) -- Guilty (Tila Escalada, age 17) -- Panchita (Guadalupe Jose Valenzuela) -- Rocillo (race horse song by Guadalupe Jose Valenzuela) -- El Corrido de dos hermanos (Ballad of two brothers by Dave and Tony Yubeta) --; Doris Seibold; SWF PRE1980.1/D.137